DEREK A. EASON



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Vision-driven change agent with career-long record of system administration, process improvement, and information technology management success for leading organizations

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established cloud technology and system administration paradigms to achieve maximum operational impacts with minimum resource expenditures. Growth-focused thought leader with a strong focus on new and emerging technologies and continual process improvement to drive operations efficiency. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as AWS architecture, network troubleshooting, and quality assurance expertise.

SELECTED HIGHLIGHTS

- Able to implement agile methodologies to optimize workflow, motivate teams, and improve process efficiency working across multiple departments, as well as multiple countries.
- Recognized for superior customer service and attention to detail, consistently surpassing project goals and achieving high customer satisfaction regarding end user support.
- Exhibit interest and ability in learning and implementing new technologies in order to drastically improve user experience and network security, and reduce downtime.

System Administration

- Networking Services
- Troubleshooting & Problem Solving
- AWS Architecture

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Cloud Technologies
- Information Technology
- Deadline Orientation
- Quality Assurance

- Scripting
- Team Leadership
- Process Improvement
- Customer Service

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALAMEDA HEALTH SYSTEM, OAKLAND, CA, 2018 TO PRESENT

IT SERVICE CENTER TECHNICIAN

- Administer remote support to more than 5000 end users for devices, systems, and applications within a multicampus healthcare setting operating 24/7.
- Diminish interruptions and response times by evaluating, prioritizing, and troubleshooting end-user issues, escalating when necessary to ensure timely and accurate resolution in a Windows environment.
- Enhance organization efficiency by diagnosing and triaging technical problems, and oversee security and access permissions for groups and individuals within the Active Directory.
- Generate clear and complete documentation regarding problems addressed, as well as solutions and workarounds using the company ticketing system.

STRATEGIC SYSTEMS, GO2IT GROUP, SAN FRANCISCO BAY AREA, CA, 2015 TO 2018

DESKTOP SUPPORT SPECIALIST

- Conducted research and applied extensive technical knowledge in order to efficiently resolve customer requests by troubleshooting network issues.
- Established standard operating procedures and processes, and trained current and new technicians to effectively use updated processes and ensure support team operated cohesively.
- Directed restacks and administered end user support for over 220 users in a Windows environment, and significantly reduced downtime by diagnosing and repairing hardware, network, and software issues.
- Ensured the integrity and security of data, reports, and access by strictly adhering to company policies, established technical procedures, and operating standards.

United States Army, Worldwide Assignments, 2009 to 2015

SECTION SERGEANT

DEREK A. EASON Page 2

- Coordinated maintenance for \$5M in inventory including computers, peripherals, and other equipment.
- Directed 7 subordinates and 30 indirect reports, and verified proficiency in the latest mission-critical equipment and systems by organizing, implementing, and supervising team training initiatives.

• Contributed feedback regarding computers, satellites, and other network devices while overseeing three annual network integration evaluations, and collaborative with staff across 14 different countries.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT, 2017

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT

CERTIFICATIONS:

AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate (SOA-CO2) Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) ITIL v4 Foundations

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Website: derekeason.io

Technical Proficiencies: Windows, Linux (Red Hat, Ubuntu), servers, routers, switches, LAN, wireless LAN, Microsoft Exchange, Active Directory, Microsoft Office Suite, Kubernetes, Docker, Python, Ansible